# Andrés Romero

PhD computer vision and parallel architectures

#### **About**

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

**℃** 0178542907 **□** 0615231394

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

✓ andresrommier

• andresromero

• in romeromier

#### **Languages**

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

#### Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

## **A** Interests

My research focuses on the development and acceleration of signal processing and computer vision algorithms. A key goal of my research is to develop high performance algorithms for **visual object detection**, **tracking** and **texture description** for real-world problems. The algorithms I have worked with require comprehensive understanding of a broad set of domains: **machine learning**, **software engineering**, **computer architecture** and **statistics**.

In total, I have more than 8 years of research experience working with signal and image processing algorithms in embedded architectures. I am familiar with **ARM architectures** (ARM Cortex A9 and A15) and the **Texas Instruments C6000 DSP** family. On those platforms I have implemented many image, voice and audio processing algorithms. During my PhD I worked on the acceleration of computer vision algorithms on desktop and embedded platforms using **OpenMP** and **SIMD** instructions sets (SSE, Neon and Altivec).

Other fields of interest to me are **data science**, **natural language processing** (NLP), **data mining**, **information theory**, **complexity theory** and **cybernetics**.

## Education

2010-2013	<b>Ph.D.</b> in Computer Science	Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique, Université Paris Sud

Advisors: Lionel Lacassagne and Michèle Gouiffès

Real-time multi-target tracking: A study on color-texture covariance matrices and descriptor/operator switching.

The results of this work were considered for the ITEA/Spy european project.

2006–2008 M.Sc. Signal Processing Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)

Advisors: Héctor Pérez Meana and Mariko Nakano Miyatake

Subject: Acoustic active noise controllers in TMS320C6713DSK platforms.

2000-2005 **Telecommunications Engineering** Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

Advisor: Bohumil Psenicka

Graduation project: Acoustic active noise cancellation.

2000 **High-school** Centro Universitario México, Mexico City

Specialization in mathematics and physics

## (E) Experience

2013-2014 <b>Un</b>	niversité Paris Sud,	Orsay Faculty of Sciences	Invited researcher and teacher
---------------------	----------------------	---------------------------	--------------------------------

Research work: Covariance descriptor algorithm implementation on "Many-core" architectures (Xeon-Phi)

2012-2013 ITEA/Spy European Project R&D engineer

 $Tracking \ and \ pedestrian \ re-identification \ module, \ project \ in \ collaboration \ between \ CASSIDEAN, \ EOLAN, \ ENSTA \ and \ IEF,$ 

Université Paris Sud

2009 **Minalum de México S.A. de C.V.** R&D engineer

Brush-less DC motor controller development using PIC's

2009 **Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic** Visiting Student

Hosted by Prof. Pavel Saradnik

2007-2009 Computer security department, DGSCA, UNAM Software engineer

Emergency response team (CERT) system development.

2006-2007 **Qualcomm, Omnitracs, Mexico City, Mexico** 

Satellite and GPS surveillance system operator

2004 Electoral Institute of Oaxaca, Oaxaca, Mexico

Software engineer

Operations engineer

Pre-electoral results system for the 2004 governor and local congress elections

#### **About**

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

andresrommmier
andresromero
andresromero
andresromier

### **Languages**

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

#### Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## **Operating** systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

## **Teaching experience**

2013-2014 **ATER (Invited researcher and teacher)** 

Courses

- · SIMD instructions for image processing,
- On-line data representations (XML, DOM, XPath, XSLT),
- · Relational data bases (SQL),
- Advanced C programming,
- · Logical component and computer architecture,
- · Scilab.

2012-2013 **Laboratory teacher** 

Université Paris-Sud, France

Université Paris-Sud, France

**Courses**: SIMD instructions for image processing.

2005-2008 **Laboratory teacher** 

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Mexico

Courses:

- Digital signal processing algorithm implementations on DSP architectures,
- · Digital and analog filtering.

## Publications

### **Articles in peer-reviewed journals**

Color tracking with contextual switching: Real-time implementation on CPU

F. Laguzet, A. Romero Mier y Terán, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Journal of Real Time Image Processing (JRTIP) Special Issue on Real-Time Color Image Processing (2013). Springer, 2013

H, Perez-Meana, A Hybrid Noise Canceling Structure with Secondary Path Estimation

A. Romero, M. Nakano-Miyatake

WSEAS Recent Advances in Systems, Communications and Computers (2008) pp. 194–199. 2008

## International peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Total Bregman Divergence for Multiple Object Tracking.

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

IEEE, International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2013

#### Real-time covariance tracking algorithm for embedded systems

A. Romero Mier y Terán, L. Lacassagne, A. Hassan Zahraee, M. Gouiffès

Conference on Design & Architectures for Signal & Image Processing (DASIP) proceedings. 2013

#### Enhanced Local Binary Covariance Matrices ELBCM for texture analysis and object tracking

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

MIRAGE 2013, Berlin, Germany. ACM International Conference Proceedings Series, 2013

#### Covariance Descriptor Multiple Object Tracking and Re-Identification with Colorspace Evaluation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

ACCV 2012 Workshops, Part II, LNCS 7729 proceedings, 2012

#### Feature points tracking adaptive to saturation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Signal and Image Processing Applications (ICSIPA), 2011 IEEE International Conference on, 2011

#### Synthesis of the Low-pass and High-pass Wave Digital Filters

B. Psenicka, Francisco J. García-Ugalde, A. Romero Mier Terán *ICINCO-SPSMC*, 2008

#### Synthesis of digital structure by matrix method

B. Psenicka, F.G. Ugalde, L.E. Salguero, A. Romero

Proceedings of the 7th IASTED International Conference on Signal and Image Processing, 2005

#### **About**

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

**○** 0178542907 **□** 0615231394

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

**y** andresrommmier

andresromero in romeromier

#### Languages

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

#### Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

### **66** References

Lionel Lacassagne, Associate Professor (MCF HDR) Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique (LRI) Université Paris Sud

▼ lionel.lacassagne@lri.fr

**\( +33 0169154124** 

. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .

Michèle Gouiffès, Enseignant Chercheur Laboratoire d'Informatique pour la Mécanique et les Sciences de l'Ingénieur Université Paris Sud

**\( +33 0169858113** 

Rubén Aquino Luna,

Information Security Sub-director, DGTIC, UNAM Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

raquino@seguridad.unam.mx

**\** +52 55 56223064

. . . . . . . . . . . . . .

Bohumil Psenicka, Full-time definite C-level Professor Facultad de Ingeniería, UNAM, Mexico City, Mexico Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

**4** +52 55 56223064